Guide to the Carolynne Cline papers, 1933-1984.
Cline, Carolynne papers, 1933-1984.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Carolynne Cline papers, 1933-1984.
37-05-2112
Carolynne Helen Cline, 1915-1985.
2.4 cubic ft.,
Correspondence, course papers, scrapbooks, photograph albums, Cornelliana, memorabilia, films, audiotapes, and transcripts.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection consists of correspondence; college course work; scrapbooks; photograph albums; Cornelliana; memorabilia; two movie films pertaining to Carol Cline's senior year, Robert Cline, parents, graduation, and the Class of 1937 reunion in 1939; two tapes and transcripts of a commentary on the films, a photograph album, and two scrapbooks; two tapes of the Class of 1939 Women's Reunion, 1964; and two tapes of "Carol's Corner" interviews with Cornell-affiliated people.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Carol Cline was the Life Secretary of the Cornell Class of 1937 Women. She had a radio program in Dayton, Ohio called "Carol's Corner."
Cornell University Class of 1937.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection consists of correspondence; college course work; scrapbooks; photograph albums; Cornelliana; memorabilia; two movie films pertaining to Carol Cline's senior year, Robert Cline, parents, graduation, and the Class of 1937 reunion in 1939; two tapes and transcripts of a commentary on the films, a photograph album, and two scrapbooks; two tapes of the Class of 1939 Women's Reunion, 1964; and two tapes of "Carol's Corner" interviews with Cornell-affiliated people. Correspondents include family members, Helen Fry and other women of the Class of 1937, S. "Tom" Boon Long, and "Nifty Nine" Round Robin letters.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cline, Carolynne Helen, 1915-1985.; Cline, Robert.; Fry, Helen.; Long, S. Boon.; Cornell University--Alumni.; Cornell University.Class of 1937 Women.
Subjects:
Class reunions.; Women broadcasters.; Women college students.
Places:
Central America.; Russia.
Form and Genre Terms:
Scrapbooks.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
NOTES
Related collection:Cornell University. Class of 1937 Women. Records, #41-4-738.
CONTAINER LIST
- Carol Cline, personal letters, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Cline family letters, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
- Miscellany, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- S. "Tom" Boon Long, '37 letters, 1955-1959 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- S. "Tom" Boon Long, letters (also son), 1960-1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- S. "Tom" Boon Long, letters, photographs, 1971-1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Russian trip diary, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Carol Cline-Gould Colman letters, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Autobiography by Cline for Rural Sociology 121, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Biology lab, 1st term, freshman year, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Biology lab, 2nd term, freshman year, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Biology class notes, prelims, finals, 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Hygiene, French, History, 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- English, 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 15-16)
- English History 61, 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- French 4A and 5B prelims and exams, notes, 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- French 16 - notes and prelims, Spring terms, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- English 25, finals, prelims, papers, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- English 25, including weekly assignment sheets, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Economics 2A, 2B (with prelims and finals), 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- English 20, Public Speaking I and II (with reports), 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Psychology II, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- English 20, term papers and prelim, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- English 50A, Sociology - Fall, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Public Speaking 30 (Phonetics), 1935 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Public Speaking 41 - theatre, play production, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Philosophy 8A and 8B term reports, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Economics 50B, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- English 42 and Public Speaking 45, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Public Speaking 45, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Rural Sociology 121, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Psychology 16A, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- English 90 - Greek Tragedy, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- English 46 - Shakespeare Tragedies, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- English 72 - Modern Poets, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- English 90 - Ibsen Plays, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- English 46 - Shakespeare, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Public Speaking 42, Psychology 16A - with prelims (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Exam schedule and personal note, 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Songs and yells compiled and written (?) by the 1937 freshman class cheerleader; Cornell songs (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Blue scrapbook, 1933-1936 (Box 2)
- Green scrapbook, 1935-1940 (Box 2)
- My Memory Book, photograph album, 1933-1939 (Box 2)
- Cornell Dramatic Club Key; Sigma Delta Tau sorority pin; Mortar Board pin; Raven & Serpent pin; small sterling silver frog hanging from bar pin; SDT pledge pin; football player toy; Ferdinand the Bull; Mortar Board silver and gold tassel and white Arts College tassel; Kitty Co-ed doll; Phi Beta Kappa "Key"; key and watch, props used in production of "Alice in Wonderland"; toy plastic jumping frog (Box 3)
- 1 reel film: Robert Cline, '39, and parents, graduation; '37 reunion, 1939 (Box 3)
- 1 reel film: Carol Cline's senior year, 1937 (Box 3)
- "Nifty Nine" Round Robin letters, 1938-1943 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- "Nifty Nine" Round Robin letters, 1944-1955 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Letters from Helen E. Fry, 1944-1945 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Central American diary - parts I and II, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Central American diary - parts III, IV and V, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- "Carol's Corner", tr. 2423
- "Carol's Corner", tr. 2424
- 1939 Women's 25th Reunion, 1964; tr. 2425
- 1939 Women's 25th Reunion Banquet, 1964; tr. 2426
- Commentary on 2 films, photo album and 2 scrapbooks, 1982; tr. 1759
- Same as tr. 1759, tr. 3818a
- Transcription of tr. 1759, trsc. 1759
- Transcription of tr. 1759, tr. 3818a, trsc. 3818a